# Brandon Crews Full Web Developer

979-209-9113, bdc1978@gmail.com

Portfolio: GitHub: LinkedIn:

bdcrews.github.io/portfolio/ www.github.com/bdcrews www.linkedin.com/in/brandon-crews/

### Summary

Full stack web developer candidate skilled in writing, clean, testable code. Experienced with React, jQuery, Node, JavaScript, and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Experienced with modern tooling and excited to pick up the right tools for the job. Over 13 years of experience as an accomplished Software Engineer.

#### Skills

<u>Advanced</u>: JavaScript (ES5, ES6, & JSX), React, jQuery, Node.js, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs, AJAX, C, C++.

**Proficient**: MongoDB and Responsive mobile-first design, TDD with Mocha, Node.js, Express, Morgan.

### **Recent Projects**

Baby Ready: A full stack app that helps moms-to-be stay organized. Built with React, Bootstrap,

Node, Express and Mongo.

**Live:** <a href="https://bookkeeper-ape-63565.netlify.com/">https://bookkeeper-ape-63565.netlify.com/</a>
Repo I: <a href="https://github.com/bdcrews/baby-ready">https://github.com/bdcrews/baby-ready</a>

Repo II: <a href="https://github.com/bdcrews/baby-ready-server">https://github.com/bdcrews/baby-ready-server</a>

Maintenance A MEAN stack app where the user can track repair and status on equipment. Built

<u>Logger</u>: with HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, NodeJS, and AJAX.

Live: https://dry-tor-47578.herokuapp.com/

Repo: <a href="https://github.com/bdcrews/maintenance-logger">https://github.com/bdcrews/maintenance-logger</a>

Find Similar: Gives recommendations and helps you discover new media. Built with HTML5, CSS3,

and jQuery. Accesses the Tastedive API.

Live: <a href="https://bdcrews.github.io/FindSimilar/">https://bdcrews.github.io/FindSimilar/</a>
Repo: <a href="https://github.com/bdcrews/FindSimilar">https://github.com/bdcrews/FindSimilar</a>

## Experience

### Capsher Technology

Senior Software Developer

College Station, TX

June 2010 – January 2013

Designed and implemented mobile, web, and desktop applications for the oilfield services company,
 Schlumberge.

Raytheon Company Dallas, TX
Senior Software Engineer June 2001 – March 2010

• Silent Knight Radar Program (January 2009 – March 2010)

- O Designed and implemented device drivers for the radar, including Gimbal Control, 1553 Communications, and other FPGA devices.
- Joint Strike Fighter (JSF) Program (February 2008 January 2009)

- Integrated and debugged device drivers for custom processors boards used in the JSF Aircraft (February 2008 – January 2009)
- Multi-Mission Maritime Aircraft (MMA) Program (July 2005 February 2008)
  - O Design and develop real-time, embedded software on a multiprocessor system interacting with radar hardware.
  - Led the software integration efforts for the BIT, Engineering Data Recording, and the Track While Scan feature.
    - Produced software requirements, schedules, test plans for the Data Recording and Track While Scan functionality as well as the updated legacy software.
  - Worked closely with suppliers to integrate their new and untested Board Support Packages.
- CV-22 Flight Test Extension (July 2001 July 2005)
  - Integrate and debug safety critical, real-time embedded software on a multiprocessor system that interact with radar hardware.
  - Electrical and System Engineering to quickly diagnose system issues and support rapid software release for the customer.

#### **Arkansas Center for Technology**

Fayetteville, AR

Software Engineer

1999 – 2001

- Designed and developed instruction tools for use by the college of education at the University of Arkansas.
- Planned, developed, integrated, and supported the UofA College of Engineering's web site.

#### Education

**THINKFUL** 

May 2017 - October 2017

Full-Stack Web Development

- Completed intensive, six month course on modern full stack JavaScript development.
- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

#### **Southern Methodist University**

Dallas, TX

M.S., Software Engineering

2005

**University of Arkanasas** 

Fayetteville, AR

B.S., Computer Systems Engineering

2001